<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hoa-thai-nguyen-22949611b</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 10:27:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Nguyen Thai Hoa's Resume]]></title><description><![CDATA[Overview My name is Hoa, and I have extensive engineering experience in the software industry. I have a T-shaped knowledge across various…]]></description><link>https://www.linkedin.com/in/hoa-thai-nguyen-22949611b/resume/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.linkedin.com/in/hoa-thai-nguyen-22949611b/resume/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Hoa, and I have extensive engineering experience in the software industry. I have a T-shaped knowledge across various fields, and my primary expertise is in front-end development, with a focus on React Js and React Native. I also possess secondary expertise in back-end development (NodeJs and GraphQL) and Cloud (AWS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am capable of working independently or as a leader of small or medium-sized teams. I currently reside in Ho Chi Minh City with my family, which includes my two daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thaihoa311@gmail.com&quot;&gt;thaihoa311@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/hoa-thai-nguyen-22949611b/&quot;&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/hoa-thai-nguyen-22949611b/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preferred working mode: Hybrid, Remote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Working experiences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;National Australia Bank - Innovation Centre of Vietnam (NICV)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Digital Identity &amp;#x26; Access - Engineer Manager / February 2022 until now&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led a cross functional (Frontend and Quality Engineers) and locations (HCMC and Melbourne) team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for team&apos;s delivery plan and ensure the team were clear about the plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Established team processes to ensure the team members knew what they should do in common scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for application quality, supported quality engineers to define testing process to improve the quality of products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In charge of driving technical direction for the team:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consulted with Architect to make decisions regarding the front-end architecture in DI&amp;#x26;A domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Involved in shaping and desiging new projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent 40% time for hands-on coding, contributing to team delivery and code review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided T-shirt sizing (draft estimation) for new features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for team building:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided feedback and mentoring engineers in the team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had regular 1-1 catch up with the team members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In charge of recruiment for the team on both sides: HCMC and Melbourne.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies used: ReactJs, React Native, TypeScript, AWS (ECS), Jenkins, NodeJs, GraphQL, Docker, Terraform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achievements:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained and developed a micro-frontend application for authentication, which has become one of the most widely-used micro-frontend apps at NAB, having been utilized by more than 10 different applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led the team to aqquire knowledge on React Native and succesfully built one of the first React Native mini-app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All micro-frontend apps have CI/CD pipelines set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributed to the core front-end library of NAB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led the team to do a presentation to NAB Group CEO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did 1 public presentation &quot;Micro-frontend and how we use it at NAB&quot; for the company. The presentation was live-broadcasted on Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/NABVietnam/videos/5447032168651073&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/NABVietnam/videos/5447032168651073&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Digital Identity &amp;#x26; Access - Lead Engineer &amp;#x26; Scrum Master / February 2021 to February 2022&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in technical design to make sure the relevant stakeholders aligned with the solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent 80% time for coding and code review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilicated sprint grooming and planning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supported and mentored other team members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributed in CI/CD pipeline configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies used: ReactJs, TypeScript, AWS ECS, Jenkins, NodeJs, GraphQL, Docker, Terraform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achievements:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successfully delivered an employee facing mini-app that helps NAB banker manages and supports customers authentication details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained and upgraded a reusable mini-app that provides login experiences for multiple applications at NAB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did multiple inernal presentations about team&apos;s products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Digital Identity &amp;#x26; Access - Senior Engineer / February 2020 to February 2021&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in technical design to make sure the relevant stakeholders aligned with the solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent most of time for coding and code review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supported and mentored other team members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributed in CI/CD pipeline configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies used: ReactJs, TypeScript, AWS, Jenkins, NodeJs, GraphQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achievements:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took charge of a reusable mini-application that delivers seamless login experiences across multiple applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed, developed, and implemented a CI pipeline for a JavaScript library that simplifies Single Sign-On integration for applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributed to team&apos;s showcases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Trusting Social&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Senior engineer / June 2019 to Feb 2020&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participated in coding and code review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborated with Back-end and QA teams to ensure high quality, efficient and reliable web applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for designing, estimating front-end components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with DevOps to deploy the Dockerized front-end app to Google Cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies: ReactJs, Docker, TypeScript, NodeJs, JAM stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achievements:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivered a single-page application that enables users to perform AI-based operations, such as facial recognition, text extraction, and face comparison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successfully developed the company&apos;s website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a reusable solution for the admin portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lazada Tech Hub Vietnam&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Manager / 2018 to 2019&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aligned development objectives with business goals in collaboration with product managers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted code reviews, mentored junior developers and ensured adherence to coding standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked with product managers to identify and prioritize development tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilized Alibaba&apos;s front-end technologies to develop, test, and maintain web applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributed as a member of the transition team in migrating the legacy Lazada tech stack to the Alibaba stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies used: ReactJs, Weex, Rax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Senior Engineer / 2014 to 2018&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed and maintained the company&apos;s e-commerce platform using ReactJs and Redux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborated with Back-end and QA teams to ensure high quality, efficient and reliable web applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted code reviews, provided technical guidance to junior developers and ensured compliance with coding standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pyramid Consulting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Junior Developer / 2011 to 2014&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked collaboratively with senior developers to implement front-end designs using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisted in the development of client websites, including creating responsive layouts and optimizing page load times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained and updated existing web applications to ensure compatibility with modern web browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrated proficiency in jQuery and AJAX for dynamic and interactive front-end functionalities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognized for exceptional problem-solving skills and ability to quickly learn new technologies, including HTML5, CSS3 and BackboneJs library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Skills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front-end development: TypeScript, ReactJs, React Native, CSS, Styled Components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back-end development: ExpressJs, NodeJs, GraphQL, Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud: AWS, Terraform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soft-skills: leadership, presentation, documentation, coaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Education &amp;#x26; Certifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;AWS Cloud Practitioner certification&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valid until 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ho Chi Minh City University of Science&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bachelor degree of Information Technology / 2008 - 2011&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>